#### **ONASAYO JAMES**

1, Awofisayo Off Alhaji Alli Lane, Ogba Road, Agege, Lagos State. onasayodotun@gmail.com, | LinkedIn: ONASAYO JAMES | +2349037919532

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

A qualified and passionate Physiotherapist. I am currently a physiotherapy graduate with clinical and work experience cutting across research development, leadership, volunteering, project management, and clinical intervention. Through my study, I have gained a lot of clinical experience and intervention management including clinical assessment, health education, patient examination, and evaluation as well as treatment. I possess strong time management, communication, leadership, and interpersonal skills.

### **CORE SKILLS**

Health Education | Teaching | Physiotherapy Procedure | Patient Education | Clinical Reasoning | Clinical Assessment | Health Advocacy | First Aid Management | Report Writing | Critical Thinking | Documentation and Evaluation | Time Management Skills | Emotional Intelligent | Attention to details | Multitasking | Effective Communication | Interpersonal Skills | Computer Skills | Project Management | Leadership | Organizational and Management Skills | Team Work | Analytical Skills | Research Writing | Decision Making | Creativity | Microsoft Office Software | Problem Solving | Graphic Design

### **EDUCATION**

# Obafemi Awolowo University – Ile-Ife, Nigeria

September 2017 – September 2023

Bachelor of Medical Rehabilitation, Physiotherapy with Credit.

Completed courses in basic medical sciences, pharmacology, physiotherapy, cardiopulmonary, radiology, pediatrics and clinical rotations with in-depth acquisition of basic medical knowledge.

# Obafemi Awolowo University - Center for Distance learning, Moro, Ile-Ife, Nigeria

2016 - 2017

A' Levels Joint University and Preliminary and Examination Board (JUPEB).

Undertook courses in Advance level Microbiology, Botany, Zoology, Chemistry, Physics with excellent performance in all registered subjects.

West African Senior School Certificate, 2009 – 2015 Undertook courses in Basic sciences, English Language, mathematics with excellent performance in WAEC (West African Examination Certificate) in all registered subjects.

#### RESEARCH

Cross cultural adaptation and psychometric testing of the using Functional Independence measure in Stroke Survivors, 2023.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Research Assistant

## Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife, Nigeria

2022 - 2023

- Work with a supervisor to develop research writing skills and participate in carrying out a research project.
- Involve in all aspects of research writing including data collection, sampling and data analysis under supervision
- Analyze collected data and draw out appropriate conclusions
- Assists with teaching, tutorials and focus group discussions for student in the preclinical classes
- Provided academic materials for students in pre-clinical classes.

# **Physiotherapist Assistant**

# Obafemi Awolowo University Teaching Hospital, Ile-Ife, Nigeria

2017 - 2023

- Engaged in patient's assessment including clerking and careful examination of patients.
- Reviewed physician referrals and patient medical records to formulate an accurate diagnosis and best course of treatment
- Assisted in carrying out physiotherapeutic services under the supervision of a licensed physiotherapist
- Participated in ward rounds, ground and teaching rounds, in service training and other educational activities.
- Implemented treatment programs as directed by a licensed physiotherapist including patient education

# Physiotherapist clinical Affiliate, National Orthopedic hospital, Igbobi, Lagos State

2021

- Engaged in 2 months outside clinical posting experience in the above-named institution
- Clerked, interviewed, reviewed patients by taking vital signs as appropriate to clinical operations
- Assisted with routine medical procedures as appropriate to training
- Promoted patient safety by maintaining a clean hygienic condition either during outpatient or ward round routine
- Worked in various unit carrying out different procedures

• Implemented treatment programs as directed by a licensed physiotherapist including patient education

### **VOLUNTEER ACTIVITIES**

Fellow, Millenium Campus Network.

**July 2022 - December 2022** 

Making social impact with SDG -3 in view (good health and wellbeing). Impacted more than 200+ lives and also led a team of volunteers for a market health outreach, educating them about reducing the risks of trauma amidst others. Vitals signs were taken free of cost.

# Ile-Ife Heritage Marathon, Osun State.

September 2021, February 2022

Race Official to ensure athletes are well attended to when injured by providing first aid treatment.

# Physiotherapist Volunteer, Special funfitness Olympics, Ibadan

2022

Accessed athletes and helped in their treatment process

# Ambassador, Sickle cell society, OAU chapter

February 2021 - Present

Actively promoting an education, prevention and sensitization campaign on sickle cell disorder amongst the teeming population with the youth at the center of contact.

# Volunteer, Red cross society, OAU chapter

February 2021 - January 2023

Work towards administering first aid treatment to injured victims as well as educating people on how to attend to emergency situations without panicking.

Volunteer, Physiotherapy Day of Service (PTDOS), 2021, 2022, 2023.

Rise of 100 leaders, Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife, Osun State.

Participant National Association of Physiotherapy Student convention, 2021, 2023.

### **CERTIFICATION**

- Center for Bioethics and Research, 2021
- Flag-System and Stratified Care International
- Indiana University Confirmation Certificate on Recognizing Plagiarism
- FIFA Diploma in Football Medicine, 2022
- Medical Imaging for Physiotherapists
- Global Physiotherapy Day of Service, 2021, 2022

• Let's Break the Chain of COVID-19 Infection, 2019

# **LEADERSHIP**

Director of Sports, National Association of Physiotherapists Students (NAPS)

# **REFEREES**

# Prof. Adedeji Bukola,

Department of Zoology, Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile Ife, Nigeria. bbkadedeji@oauife.edu.ng +2348055327066

# Prof. A.T. Onigbinde,

Department of Physiotherapy, University of Medical Sciences, Ondo State, Nigeria. aonigbinde@unimed.edu.ng +2347057682042

# Dr T.O. Awotidebe,

Department of Physiotherapy, Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife, Osun State, Nigeria. tidebez@yahoo.com +2348037196021